Guide to the Judith Hennessee Papers, 1950s-1999
Judith Hennessee papers 1950s-1999
Hennessee, Judith Adler
3.5 Linear Feet 2140 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers may not attribute quotations from transcripts designated "Off" or "Off the record."
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in the Duke University Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Judith Hennessee Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2000.
Biographical Note
Biographer of feminist Betty Friedan and member of the National Organization for Women.
Collection Overview
The collection primarily contains materials related to Hennessee's writing career and her participation in the National Organization for Women (NOW). Most of the NOW materials concern its 1972 petition to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to deny renewal of WABC-TV's license due to alleged discrimination against women in programming and employment. Included are legal documents; information related to NOW's monitoring study of WABC; reports pertaining to ABC and other television networks; and materials concerning the portrayal of women in the broadcast and print media, including several issues of the Media Report to Women newsletter. Other feminist materials include clippings, reports, political buttons and stickers, publications, and printed material, including several issues of the feminist literary magazine aphra and various women's organizations' newsletters. The collection also includes interview transcripts and other research materials for, correspondence about, and both a typescript and a published copy of Hennessee's biography Betty Friedan: Her life. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hennessee, Judith Adler
Friedan, Betty
Friedan, Betty; --Biography.
National Organization for Women
National Organization for Women -- Trials, litigation, etc.
National Organization for Women -- History
American Broadcasting Company
United States. Federal Communications Commission
Feminists -- United States
Feminism -- United States
Feminism -- United States -- Periodicals
Television broadcasting policy -- United States
Television broadcasting -- Social aspects -- United States
Television -- Law and legislation -- United States
Women in television broadcasting -- United States
Women on television -- United States
Clippings
Aphra.
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Contents of Collection
- Judith Hennessee Papers, 1950s-1999
  - NOW petition to deny renewal of WABC-TV's FCC license, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Analyses of and reports on gender and the media, including WABC-TV, 1970s (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1970s (Box 3)
  - Clippings: Betty Friedan, 1980s-1990s
  - Reviews of Betty Friedan: Her Life, 1999
  - Various feminist publications, 1970s
  - NOW publications, 1971 (Box 4)
  - NY Radical Feminists Conference on Rape, 1971
  - Feminist buttons and stickers
  - Typescript of Betty Friedan
  - Clippings: articles by and about Betty Friedan, 1950s-1990s (bulk 1970s)
  - Correspondence regarding Betty Friedan, 1998
  - Transcripts of phone interviews, 1994-1997, (Folders 1-2 of 5)
    [Researchers may not attribute quotations from transcripts designated "Off" or "Off the record."]
  - Transcripts of phone interviews, 1994-1997, (Folders 3-5 of 5) (Box 5)
  - Analysis of WABC-TV Responses (Removed from Box 2) (Box 6)
  - Articles about Betty Friedan (Removed from Box 3-4)